marineenergy.biz 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy - Navingo

**1\. Introduction**  
Navingo takes your privacy seriously. We process the information about you (the person concerned) in a safe way. In this Privacy Statement we explain what data we process and why we use your data. Besides that, you can find information about your rights with regards to the processing of your personal data. We advise you to carefully read the Privacy Statement. If you have any questions, please contact info@navingo.com.

**2\. Who is Navingo?**  
Navingo B.V. a limited liability company incorporated under the laws of the Netherlands, with its registered office in Schiedam, the Netherlands, and its principle place of business at Jan van Galenstraat 56 (3115 JG), Schiedam and is listed in the Chamber of Commerce under number 27197825.

With regards to the processing of your personal data. Navingo is the responsible party for the following platforms: Events; Offshore Energy Exhibition & Conference, Maritime & Offshore Career Event, Dredging Today Conference, Offshore Energy Stakeholders Meeting Publications; Maritime Holland Magazine and Business Guide, Offshore WIND Magazine, International Business Guide and Vessel Directory, Offshore Holland, Maritieme & Offshore Carrièregids, Career Update, Dredging Today Vessel Directory News Portals; OffshoreEnergyToday.com, OffshoreWIND.biz, MarineEnergy.biz, MaritiemNieuws.nl, DredgingToday.com, LNGWorldNews.com, NavalToday.com, SubseaWorldNews.com, WorldMaritimeNews.com Job Portals; OffshoreEnergy.jobs, OffshoreWind.jobs, OilGasCareer.nl, Dredging.Jobs, MaritiemeVacaturebank.nl, OffshoreWIND.jobs, MaritimeCareer.com

**3\. How does Navingo use your data?**  
Below you can find an overview of the reasons why Navingo processes personal data about you. An indication is made which data Navingo uses, for which specific purpose it is used, and what the legal basis is for processing the information.

Newsletters

If you have indicated that you want to receive our newsletter, you will receive this periodically. Depending on the newsletter of the platform you subscribed to, we could use your e-mail address, first name and last name.

The basis of processing this data is the execution of your unequivocal permission. This means that you can withdraw your permission at any time.

Ticketing - Events

For the ticketing of our events we gather personal data as well as additional information about your background and industry. Depending on which event you attend, your name, job title, educational level/information and company name may be gathered and/or printed on your visitor badge that is in fact your entry ticket to the events. Your email address will be used to send you your e-ticket.

Your background information such as: role, business activity, decision making authority, sector, etc. will be used will be processed anonymously and will be used for:

Photo/Video recording  
Navingo will be recording their events by taking pictures and recording videos. This footage (pictures and videos) is also subject to being shared on our (social) media channels for promotional purposes. These recordings are going to take place on the day you are in attendance of the event. By agreeing on the terms of our Privacy Policy, Navingo is granted in using this footage with possible recordings of yourself in our photos and/or videos. Explicit consent is not sought from individuals. In case of any given interview, you will be informed (verbally) prior to the recording taking place of the purpose of the recording and where it will be made available.

Exhibitor Services - Events  
Exhibitors of our events will be granted access to an exhibitor portal. Services in this portal may include but are not limited to:

The basis of processing this data is our justifiable interest to provide our services.

CV information – Job Portals

Create account  
When you create an account you the following data about you is processed; First name, last name, sex, e-mail address, password, date of birth, address, postal code, city of residence, country, nationality, (mobile) telephone number, applications and CV-data such as, career level, aspired job position, availability, information about your educational institution, working experience, language proficiency, courses, references, computer skills, extracurricular activities, hobbies, drivers licence.

When you indicate that you want to be found by companies who have vacancies on the website. The data that is collected pertains to information that is relevant for companies in order to decide if they would like to have an interview with you. This could be your personal data and CV information. When you create your account, you are able to indicate if you would like your CV information to be anonymised. If you would like to change this setting at a later moment, you can always go back into your account and change your settings or delete your account.

The basis of processing this data is the execution of the agreement that Navingo closes with you about usage of the website. This data is saved for as long as you have an account on the job portal.

Reacting to vacancies

Through the job portals, you can also apply personally to vacancies that are offered on the website without having created an account. We will then process the following data: name & address details, contact information, options CV. This information is provided to the concerning employer.

The basis of processing this data is the execution of the agreement that job portals closes with you about usage of the website. Afterwards, the concerning employer is responsible for handling the data.

Analytics  
In order to get a clear picture of the quality and effectivity of our website, we use Google Analytics and similar tools. The program uses the following data about you: IP address (last 8 numbers hidden), global location (at country level), surfing behaviour (which companies you visited and amount of time you spent on a specific page).

The basis of processing this data is our justifiable interest in wanting to improve our website.

Matchmaking  
The OEEC Matchmaking program makes use of the Networktables software. If you opt-in for Offshore Energy Matchmaking, registration data such as your name, company name, job title and sector information may be shared for functional reasons. You can optionally enter more information to your profile at Networkworktables platform that will also be shared online. On the platform attendees can also exchange their contact details, but only if both parties consent. If other attendees contact you on the Networktables platform you will be notified through an email from Networktables of Offshore Energy (approximately once a week).

**4\. How do we receive your personal data?**  
Navingo has received your personal data, because you have provided this data to us.

**5\. What are your rights?**  
Under the European General Data Protection Regulation you have several rights with regards to your data and the processing of your data:

Insight  
You can always check your own (personal) data and if need, adjust in your account. If you would like to know which personal data you provided to Navingo, you can send a request for insight.

Adjust  
If you would like to adjust your personal data based on your request for insight and you are unable to do this yourself through your account, you can send a request for adjustment at Navingo. You can request Navingo to adjust, improve, adapt, remove or (partly) hide your data.

Limiting the processing of data  
Besides this, you will have the right, under certain conditions, to request Navingo to limit the processing of your personal data.

Right of objection  
If processing certain data is done under ‘justifiable interest’ by Navingo or a third party, you have the right to object to the processing of this data.

Data transfer  
You have the right to request Navingo to send your personal data. Navingo will provide this to you in a structured and common form, which can be opened in other usual digital systems. This way you can also accommodate your data at another provider.

Automated processing  
In all instances where a decision is made about you based on the automated processing of personal data, you have the right to request Navingo to reconsider this decision by a person. You can always inform us about your point of view, or let us know that you do not agree with our decision.

Revoke permission  
In all cases where the basis of processing your data is the execution of your unequivocal permission, you have the right to revoke your permission. This has no consequences for the past, but it does mean that we are no longer able to process this data. This may mean that Navingo is unable to provide you with certain services.   

Reaction by Navingo  
Requests may be sent to info@navingo.com. Navingo will grant your request as soon as possible, with a maximum of one (1) month after Navingo received such a request. In case Navingo rejects your request, we will inform you why the request was rejected.

**6\. Recipients of data**  
The information may be passed on to parties Navingo works with to process data, including – but not limited to - : E-mark Mail, Copernica, E-concepts, Webstecks, HVMP, Salesforce, Exonet, Piwik, SmartAdServer, Twinfield, Otys, Instant Magazine, Winsys, Microsoft, Axoft, KPN, SMPT, Drukkerij Crezee, Amsterdam RAI, Adexpo, Arti 70, CEVA, Survey Monkey, Uptrends, Add This, CloudFare, DigitalOcean, LevelLevel, Online Department, Leedfeeder, TriplePro, Networktables.

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include the trusted third parties listed above who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

**7\. Pass data on to third countries or international organisations**  
For technical or operational reasons, it may be possible that your data is passed on to companies that are affiliated to Navingo which are located outside of the European Economic Area. Since the regulations concerning privacy protection may not offer the same level of protection as within the European Economic Area, Navingo uses the Privacy Shield by the EU Model Clauses to protect your privacy as much as possible. If this is not possible, Navingo will ask your permission to pass your (personal) data to countries without a suitable protection level. You may revoke your permission at any time.

**8\. What are cookies and how does Navingo use them?**  
Cookies are small pieces of (text) information that are sent to your browser when you visit the online platforms by Navingo, and are then saved on the hard drive or memory of your computer, tablet, mobile phone or other device (hereafter: Device). The cookies placed through the websites of Navingo will not damage your Device or the files saved onto that Device. When we refer to cookies, we do not only mean these small pieces of (text) information, but also comparable techniques used to collect information, such as device fingerprinting.

The websites by Navingo use functional, analytical and sometimes tracking cookies.

The functional cookies are used to track when you  have logged into a site, visited certain pages or clicked certain buttons. They are also used to personalize your experience: your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs. Lastly they are used to improve our website. We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.

The analytical cookies are used to collect statistics about usage of our websites. Navingo uses Google Analytics, which has been set to ‘privacy friendly’, in line with the instructions by General Protection Regulation. This means that the data collected is anonymously when possible, and that Google will never process your complete IP-address, but will always hide the last 8 numbers. Google does not use the data for its own interests because Navingo has not given Google permission to use the data for this purpose. Navingo does not make use any other Google services in combination with the Google Analytics cookies. The collected data is saved by Google on servers that are located in the United States. Navingo has a processing agreement with Google, Inc. For more information, please refer to the [privacy policy](https://www.google.nl/intl/nl/policies/technologies/cookies/) of Google Analytics. If you do not want to accept Google Analytics cookies, please click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=nl).

With tracking cookies, also known as marketing cookies, advertisers (third parties) can track visitors and their surfing behavior. With this information a visitor profile can be created.

If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly.

**9\. Where can you deposit your questions or complaints?**  
Should you have any questions about this Privacy Statement and the way Navingo processes your data, you can send an e-mail to info@navingo.com. If you have a complaint about the way Navingo processes your data, you can also send an e-mail to info@navingo.com. Besides that you can always contact the national authority on this field. In the Netherlands this is the ‘Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens’.

**10\. Storage Period**  
Navingo does not save personal data longer than necessary for the above mentioned purposes or as long as necessary to comply with the laws and regulations.

**11\. Security**  
Navingo has implemented appropriate technical and organisational measurements in order to secure personal data of Users against loss or wrongful processing of data.

**12\. Amendments to Privacy Statement**  
Navingo has the right to make amendments to this Privacy Statement. Each amendment will be announced on this page. Navingo advises those involved to check this page regularly to see if any adjustments were made.

The current privacy statement has been updated on 07 February 2019.
